A Finding Aid to the Werner Drewes Papers, 1838-2015, bulk 1890-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.drewwern
Archives of American Art
Werner Drewes papers
bulk 1890-1990
1838-2015
AAA.drewwern
Archives of American Art
15.6 Linear feet
The papers of painter, printmaker, designer, and teacher, Werner Drewes, measure 15.6 linear feet and date from 1838-2015, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1890s-1990s. The papers document Drewes' life and career through biographical and family material; correspondence with family members, artists, galleries, and art institutions and organizations; scattered teaching notes and writings including a diary; catalogs and inventories of artwork; three scrapbooks; printed material; 38 sketchbooks, loose sketches, and prints; and photographs of Drewes, his family, friends and colleagues, exhibitions, travels, and works of art. Also found are scattered papers of Drewes' second wife, Maria Drewes.
Drewes, Werner, 1899-1985
Scope and Contents note
The papers of painter, printmaker, designer, and teacher, Werner Drewes, measure 15.6 linear feet and date from 1838-2015, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1890s-1990s. The papers document Drewes' life and career through biographical and family material; correspondence with family members, artists, galleries, and art institutions and organizations; scattered teaching notes and writings including a diary; catalogs and inventories of artwork; three scrapbooks; printed material; 38 sketchbooks, loose sketches, and prints; and photographs of Drewes, his family, friends and colleagues, exhibitions, travels, and works of art. Also found are scattered papers of Drewes' second wife, Maria Drewes.
Biographical material documents Drewes' family history through family trees and biographical notes made by family members, and also includes 3 of Drewes' passports, some student and military records, resumés, and a partial interview transcript.
Correspondence is with family members; artists including Ed Boccia, Thomas Eldred, T. Lux Feininger, Clark Fitzgerald, Wassily Kandinsky, Jean Helion, Gerhard Marcks, Arthur Osver, Karl Schrag, and Albert Urban; and galleries and art organizations and institutions such as Richard York Gallery, the Smithsonian Institution, and others. Correspondence also relates to the Drewes estate, as well as to loans, exhibitions and sales of artwork.
Notes and writings include a diary kept by Drewes between 1918-1920 in Europe, a "love letter" in verse form written by Drewes to his first wife, Margaret, some teaching notes and notes on design, and 2 essays about Drewes written by others.
Catalogs and inventory records provide comprehensive documentation of the artwork Drewes created over the course of his career. Entries include titles, assigned numbers, subjects, dimensions, media used, and sketches or photos of artwork.
Three scrapbooks provide scattered documentation of Drewes' life and career, and include clippings from the 1920s and 1930s, and a scrapbook created by Maria Drewes for her husband's memorial service.
Printed material includes event announcements and exhibition catalogs, as well as news clippings tracing Drewes' career from the 1920s to the 1980s.
Artwork consists of greeting cards made by Drewes, as well as 38 sketchbooks and numerous loose sketches in pencil, ink, watercolor, and crayon.
Photographic material includes vintage family photographs, prints, negatives, slide tranparencies, and 8 glass plate negatives, of Drewes, his family and friends, events including exhibitions and travels, and artwork.
Found in Maria Drewes' papers are correspondence, 17 diaries primarily documenting travels with Werner Drewes, two scrapbooks with designs for jewelry, and photos of family, friends and jewelry.
Biographical/Historical note
Painter, printmaker and designer Werner Drewes (1899-1985) was born in Canig, Germany, and immigrated to the United States in 1930. A student of the Bauhaus, and a prolific artist and teacher, Drewes worked with many kinds of media and produced numerous woodcuts, etchings, oils, watercolors, drawings and collages over the course of his life.
Drewes served for two years on Germany's Western Front during World War 1, before studying at the Bauhaus, Weimar, from 1921-1922. He then traveled throughout Europe, Asia and North and South America with his wife Margaret before returning to Germany in 1927 and enrolling at the Bauhaus, Dessau. During his time there Drewes forged his artistic ideas from the radical influences of renowned architects and artists including Lyonel Feininger, Johannes Itten, Wassily Kandinsky, Paul Klee, and Oscar Schlemmer, and learned the Bauhaus teaching approach that would serve him throughout his career. In 1930 Drewes, Margaret, and their 2 young sons emigrated to the United States and settled in New York City where Drewes attended the Art Students League. From 1935-1936 he taught drawing and printmaking at the Brooklyn Museum School as an employee of the Works Progress Administration Federal Art Project (WPA FAP). In 1936 he became a founding member of American Abstract Artists and the following year joined the American Artists' Congress and became an American citizen. From 1937-1940 he taught painting and printmaking at Columbia University.
In the early 1940s Drewes taught at the Master Institute in Riverside Museum, New York City, and worked as a technical supervisor for the Graphic Art Division of the FAP. From 1944-1945 he worked at Stanley William Hayter's Atelier 17 improving his intaglio technique and then teaching design, printmaking and photography at Brooklyn College. In 1946 he taught design at the Institute of Design in Chicago before being appointed Professor of Design at the School of Fine Arts of Washington University in Saint Louis, where he continued to teach until his retirement in 1965.
Following Margaret's death in 1959, Drewes married jewelry designer and fellow professor of Washington University, Mary (Maria) Louise Lischer in 1960. On Drewes' retirement he and Maria moved to Pennsylvania where he continued to paint, focusing primarily on still lifes and landscapes. He moved to Washington in 1972 and published his American Indians portfolio, before finally setting in Reston, Virginia, where the Rose Catalog of his prints was published and where he lived as a working and exhibiting artist until his death in 1985.
In October 1984 a comprehensive retrospective, Sixty-Five Years of Printmaking, was held at the then named Smithsonian's National Museum of American Art. Drewes' work can be found in the collections of the Brooklyn Museum, the Metropolitan Museum of Art, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Museum of Modern Art, National Gallery of Art, New York Public Library, Smithsonian American Art Museum, and the Whitney Museum of American Art.
Arrangement note
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1838-1980s (0.4 linear feet; Boxes 1, 16)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1878-2004 (1.2 linear feet; Boxes 1-2, 16)
Series 3: Notes and Writings, 1922-2002 (0.5 linear feet; Box 2)
Series 4: Catalogs and Inventory Records, circa 1919-circa 1980s (2.3 linear feet; Boxes 2-6)
Series 5: Scrapbooks, 1920s-1985 (3 folders; Box 5)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1897-2015 (1 linear feet; Boxes 5-6)
Series 7: Artwork and Sketchbooks, circa 1890s-2002 (3.67 linear feet; Boxes 6-9, 16-17)
Series 8: Photographic Material, circa 1890s-2000 (5.53 linear feet; Boxes 9-14, 17, MGP 2)
Series 9: Mary (Maria) Louise Lischer Drewes Papers, 1930s-1980s (1 linear foot; Box 15)
Many of the records were assigned color-coded alpha-numeric labels prior to donation. In series where these labeling systems predominate, material has been arranged according to those systems and all previously assigned labels are indicated in the Container Listing. Many folder titles are taken from the original labels. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
The collection is arranged as 9 series.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. Research Center. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Werner Drewes papers were donated in 2005 by Werner Drewes' sons Wolfram U. Drewes, Harald D. Drewes, and Bernard W. Drewes. 4 additional items were donated by Karen Seibert, Drewes granddaughter, in 2015. Some material had been previously loaned for microfilming in 1979, and was subsequently included in the 2005 gift.
Boccia, Edward, 1921-2012; Drewes, Maria; Eldred, Thomas; Feininger, T. Lux; Fitz-Gerald, Clark B., (Clark Battle), 1917-2004; Hélion, Jean, 1904-1987; Kandinsky, Wassily, 1866-1944; Marcks, Gerhard; Osver, Arthur, 1912-2006; Richard York Gallery; Schrag, Karl; Smithsonian Institution.; Urban, Albert; Art--Study and teaching; Designers--Virginia; Diaries; Educators--Virginia; Greeting cards; Interviews; Painters--Virginia--Reston; Photographs; Printmakers--Virginia--Reston; Prints; Scrapbooks; Sketchbooks; Transcripts
- Biographical Material, 1838-1980s; Series 1; 0.4 Linear feet Boxes 1, 16
  Arrangement note
  Some of the material in this series was labeled with green and yellow stickers as the "G" and "Y" series. Material is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  Scope and Contents note
  Included here are Drewes' 1923, 1926 and 1932 passports, his student record from the Bahaus School of Design signed by Mies van der Rohe and Wassily Kandinsky, some military papers, resumes and biographical notes, and an incomplete transcript of an interview with Drewes.
  Also found is information relating to Drewes' family history, including family trees, a coat of arms, family letters and notebooks, and a book of handwritten poetry belonging to Drewes' mother. Much of this material is in German.
  - Address Book (G28), circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Awards and Certificates, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bauhaus Student Record, Passports and Military Documents, 1899-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Calendar, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Family History, 1838-1930s; 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    OV material housed in Box 16, Folder 1
  - Family History (G2, G6), circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Family History Notes (G11), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Interview Transcript (incomplete) of Interview of Drewes by Martina Roudabush Norelli for the Smithsonian National Museum of American Art (Y42), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1917, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Poetry Book of Martha Schaefer (Drewes) (G10), 1880s-1890s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Resumés (Y39), circa 1960s-circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Resumés and Biographical Notes, circa 1950s-circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Who's Who Entries, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Oversized Family History from Box 1, Folder 5 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1878-2004; Series 2; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, 16
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  Found in this series are letters from Maria Drewes and other family members, and artists and art dealers including Josef Albers, Edward Boccia, Alexander Calder, Howard Dearstyne, Bourgoyne Diller, Katherine S. Dreier, Perle Fine, Adolph Gottlieb, Herbert Grainick, Jean Helion, Carl Holty, Wassily Kandinsky, Gerhard Marcks, Laszlo Moholy-Nagy, Hans Moller, Abraham Rattner, Richard York Gallery, Kurt Roesch, Karl Schrag, Albert Urban, and others. Some individual correspondents have named files, while others are included in the "General" files.
  General correspondence and general business correspondence include correspondence with art galleries, and art institutions, including the Smithsonian Institution, and relate primarily to loans, sales, and exhibitions of artwork.
  Correspondence relating to the Drewes' estate includes an appraisal report by Karen Holtzman for Drewes' artwork and correspondence between family members, including Harald and Wolfram Drewes, and inventories of artwork.
  One folder relates to a 1974 exhibition in Turkey and Greece, and includes photographs and publicity material from the exhibition. A folder of correspondence labeled with a "Y" series of yellow stickers includes letters from T. Lux Feininger, Clark Fitzgerald, Karl Schrag, and Swedish artists Jan and Pia Thunholm.
  Greeting cards consist of hand made cards sent to Drewes by artists including Gerhard Marcks, Karl Schrag and others.
  - Berlin Visit, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Boccia, Ed, 1969-1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Condolence Letters on Death of Margaret Drewes, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Drewes Estate, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Drewes Estate, Holtzmann Appraisal Report, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
  - Drewes, Mary (Maria) Louise, from Werner Drewes (Y5), circa 1960-1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Drewes, Mary (Maria) Louise, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Eldred, Edna and Thomas (Y43), circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Exhibition, Werner Drewes-Baski Sanati (1974) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Family Letters (G14, G15), 1878-1959 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - General, A-B, circa 1930s-circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - General C, 1966-1980s; 1934 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - General, D-F, circa 1930s-circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - General, G-I, circa 1940s-circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - General, J-L, 1930s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - General, M-N, 1930s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - General, O-R, 1930s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - General, S-U, 1930s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - General, V-Z, 1960s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - General, First Names Only and Illegible, circa 1970s-circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - General Business Correspondence, 1930-1945 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - General Business Correspondence, 1946-2004 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Greeting Cards, circa 1920s-circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 3-9)
    Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 2
  - Helion, Jean, 1937-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kandinsky, Wassily, 1930s-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Marcks, Gerhard and Maria, 1963-1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Osver, Arthur, 1950-1984 (Box 2, Folder 13-16)
  - Prizes and Requisitions, 1940-1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Purchases, 1956-1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Richard York Gallery, 1987-1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Schrag, Karl, 1940s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1969-1985 (Box 2, Folder 21-23)
  - Urban, Albert, 1946-1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Y Labeled Correspondence (Y15-Y36), 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Oversized Greeting Cards from Box 2, Folder 4 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Notes and Writings, 1922-2002; Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet Box 2
  Some of the material in this series is labeled with "G" and "Y" stickers as the green and yellow series.
  Series includes a biographical essay, a German diary, with translation, documenting Drewes' time in Europe from 1918-1920, a 1922 "love letter" to Drewes' first wife Margaret written in a bound notebook in verse form with a translation from the German, and notes on Drewes' trips to Europe from the 1960s-1980s.
  General notes on design and diagrams of class problems appear to have been written by Drewes' during his tenure at Washington University.
  Writings by others include two essays on Drewes.
  - By Drewes (Box 2)
    - Biographical Essay (G24), circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Diagrams of Class Problems, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Diary of Werner Drewes, English Translation, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Diary of Werner Drewes, 1918-1920, Translation of Manuscript to Modern German (G21-G23), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
    - "Farewell Love Letter to Margaret when she left for the Azores in 1922" (Y1A) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "Farewell Love Letter to Margaret when she left for the Azores in 1922," Translation (Y1B), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - General Notes on Design, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Poems, circa 1950s-circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Notes on Drewes' Trips to Europe (G27), circa 1984 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - By Others (Box 2)
    - Essay by Franz Geierhaas, English Translation (G25), "The Graphic Work of Werner Drewes", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Essay on Drewes by Riedl (Y-40), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Catalogs and Inventory Records, circa 1919-circa 1980s; Series 4; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 2-6
  The bulk of the catalogs and index cards are labeled with blue stickers as the "B" series; two folders contain "T" series index cards. All material is arranged in alpha-numerical order according to these labels.
  Series contains inventory records of artwork maintained by Drewes throughout his career from the early 1900s-1980s. Catalogs document artwork by genre and may record any or all of the following: the date of execution, title and assigned number, a sketch of the artwork with descriptive notes such as subject and dimensions, and sales information where applicable. In some cases photos of artwork are affixed beside the sketch. A series of copies of some of the catalogs, compiled from the originals in the 1980s, is also included here.
  Index cards, which document artwork arranged by number, contain similar information but are accompanied in many cases by photographs, and negatives, of artwork rather than sketches.
  - Catalog B1: Oils, 1930s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Catalogs B2, B3: Oils, 1930s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Catalog B4: Oils, 1930s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Catalog B5A: Oils, 1930s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Catalog B5B: Oils, 1930s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Catalogs B6, B7: Watercolors, 1930s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Catalogs B8, B9: Prints, circa 1919-1980s (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Catalog B10: Prints, circa 1919-1980s (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Catalog B12: Prints, circa 1919-1980s (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Catalog B13: Collages, 1940s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Catalog B14, circa 1920s-circa 1940s (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Catalog B15: Prints, circa 1919-1980s (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Catalog, Not Numbered: Prints, circa 1919-1980s (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Catalog Notes for Wolfram Drewes, circa 1940s-circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Catalog Copies, B1, R2-R4, Y2-Y3, circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  - Catalog Copies B2, B3, circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Catalog Copies B4, circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Catalog Copies B5A, B5B, circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - Catalog Copies B6, B7, circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Index Cards (Box 4)
    - Cards for 1923-1944, B16, circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Portrait Studies, 1924-1944, B16, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Paintings, 1932-1944, B17, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Paintings, 1932-1944, #191-337, B17, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Artwork, 1924-1950, #1-124, B18, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Artwork, 1924-1950, #125-241, B18, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Artwork, 1924-1950, #241-322, B18, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Artwork, 1924-1950, #322-400, B18, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Artwork, 1924-1950, #401-476, B18, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Artwork, 1924-1950, #477-526, B18, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Artwork, 1924-1950, #526-599, B18, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Artwork, 1951-1971, #600-655, B19, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Artwork, 1951-1971, #656-749, B19, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Artwork, 1951-1971, #750-800, B19, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Artwork, 1951-1971, #801-877, B19, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Artwork, 1951-1971, #878-933, B19, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Artwork, 1951-1971, #934-1016, B19, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Artwork, 1951-1971, #1017-1105, B19, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Artwork, 1951-1971, #1106-1199, B19, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Artwork, 1971-1985, #1200-1239, B20, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Artwork, 1971-19851, #1240-1298, B20, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Artwork, 1971-1985, #1299-1363, B20, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Artwork, 1971-1985, #1364-1428, B20, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Artwork, 1971-1985, #1429-1486, B20, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Artwork, 1971-1985, #1488-1535, B20, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Artwork, 1971-1985, #1536-1570, B20, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Artwork #T1-T109, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Artwork #T110-T159, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Price Lists and Miscellaneous Records, 1939, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Scrapbooks, 1920s-1985; Series 5; 3 Folders Box 5
  Three scrapbooks include fragments of a clippings scrapbook about Drewes from the 1920s-1930s, a scrapbook compilied for Drewes' memorial service, and a scrapbook of photos of artwork and clippings compiled by Rosamund Frost.
  - Fragments, 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Memorial Service for Werner Drewes (G3), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "Werner Drewes" by Rosamund Frost (G5), circa 1950 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Printed Material, 1897-2015; Series 6; 1 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  Announcements and catalogs are for Drewes' one-man shows as well as exhibitions and events in which Drewes participated.
  Other announcements and catalogs include catalogs listing sales information for Drewes' artwork and announcements and catalogs for other artists.
  Clippings are generally about Drewes and his exhibitions. Also found are 3 children's books published in Germany, one of which was a gift to Drewes as a child.
  - Book, Die Geschichten von Jan und Jon und von ihrem Lotsen-Fisch by Lou Scheper-Berkenkamp (G2), 1947 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Book, Ganz dicht am Main by Marianne Mielenhausen (G3), 1944 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Book, Wie die Tiere Soldated werden wollten by Bootticher and Fedor Finzer, circa 1897 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, circa 1920s-circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Clippings, 1920s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 12-24)
  - Drewes Announcements and Catalogs, circa 1920s-circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 25-26)
  - Drewes Announcements and Catalogs, 1930s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 27-34)
  - Drewes Announcements and Catalogs, circa 1970s-2015 (Box 6, Folder 1-12)
  - Other Announcements and Catalogs, circa 1920s-ca. 1980s (Box 6, Folder 13-16)
  - Publications, 1930s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 17-19)
- Artwork and Sketchbooks, circa 1890s-2002; Series 7; 3.67 Linear feet Boxes 6-9, 16-17
  The bulk of the material is labeled with "R" stickers as the red series and is arranged in numerical sequence.
  The bulk of Drewes' sketchbooks and groups of loose sketches, are dated and titled by subject or genre, and contain primarily pencil and ink sketches, with some crayon and watercolor sketches. Many are labeled with red stickers as the "R" series.
  Also found are 10 folders of Drewes' prints made for holiday greeting cards. An additional folder contains cards made for Maria Drewes.
  Two folders contain artwork by others, including family members.
  - Folder for "Etchings from South America" (G 8), circa 1940s (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Greeting Card Prints, 1940s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 21-30)
  - Sketchbook, 1912-1913 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Sketchbook R1: Maine, 1968 September (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Sketchbook R2: Untitled, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Sketchbook R3B: Europe, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Sketchbook R4: Trip to Europe, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Sketchbook R5: France and Greece, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Sketchbook R5A: Untitled (Mounted Sketches), 1933-1953 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 3
  - Sketchbook R6: Untitled, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbook R6: Germany, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Sketchbook R7: England, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 7)